Something to note here is that this list comprehension, it will go and build up that whole
list in memory and it's a little bit inefficient, right? In Python 3, there's a idea of generators
and like we saw when we called range, it's like, oh, here's this funky object. Calling range,
each number will be generated as we loop over a kind of just in time, think about it as a
lazy evaluation. As we work with bigger data sets, we can pretty easily do the same thing.
So here's my length for name for name and dupes. To make a generator expression, it's called
generator expression in Python, but I like to call it generator comprehension. I think that
just makes a little bit more sense. Generator expression is the kind of correct name generator
comprehension is how you can think about it. So I think that this like, you know, we are generator
object back. And just like with range, that value will be calculated as we, as we need it,
which is generally when we loop over it. And you can pass this generator comprehension into some
of our other methods. So here I'm calling a set on it. This is a lot more efficient.
When you pass in this generator comprehension to other methods, these extra parentheses are
optional. Python just knows. You can also call those other methods, the sum, the max, and the min,
on them. So the more efficient representation. Notice that when we make a generator comprehension,
and here, let me simplify a little bit. I'll just say, you know, I'll do my squares again.
We can't, like, let's say I assign it to a value. I can't do like my Gen 0, right? It, like, I could
with a list. I can't access the first item. It's not subscriptable, right? So the way that we get
at these items in the generator is we loop over them either in a comprehension or a for loop,
right? That's when these values become available as we loop over them. Any questions about
generators? Yeah. So what would you as a generator? What's the benefit to that? Is it a profound
thing? Yeah. As your data structure is grow, as you're using large numbers working with
large data sets, like you would, in AI, ML, generators become crucial, because you don't have to generate,
or Python's not creating that whole list, that whole data structure in memory. It's doing a lazy
evaluation. And I could talk, like, all day about iterators and generators. This is just
what I have enough time to cover. They're really interesting and fascinating.